Steps for labeling a diagram.
The first step is to look at the
diagram to identify what it describes.
For example, some questions require you to label
a water filter.
In step 2, you have to predict the suitable
information for each blank.
If the question's requirement is to fill in
words on the diagram, then you should pay
attention to the word limit.
In step 3, you have to listen and
fill in the correct answers.
In case you get lost, take notes immediately
and do not panic.
In step 4, after listening, you should check
your answers and never leave your answer sheet
blank.
Let's look at an example together.
In this exercise, you will listen to two
students discussing a lecture that one of them
had missed.
From the name of the diagram, you can tell
that the recording talks about the formation
of meteoroid, meteor and meteorite.
With this type, we don't have given options, so
we have to fill in the correct
answers.
The word limit is to write one word
only.
Step 2.
Predict the information in each blank.
For example, blank number 1 needs a noun
referring to something around the sun.
Blank number 2 needs a noun referring to
something on or around here.
And blank number 3 also needs a noun
referring to something in the space environment.
As you can see, it is an area
between Earth and space.
Now, you will listen to the recording and
fill in this diagram in the practice section.
Let's go!